<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Josef Monje</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://josefmonje.com/feeds%5Cjosef-monje.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 15:53:28 +0800</lastBuildDate><item><title>Software-Defined Radio</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/software-defined-radio.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It's been almost half a year since my last post! How time really flies. I've been intending to post and more often than once a month but I just haven't developed the habit. That's the bad news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is I've been busy with a lot of experimentation and some projects! I was recently involved in a hardware project and I can't resist my curiosity. My current favorite thing now is SDR or software-defined radio. It lets my computer interact with radio waves using the right gadgets. How boring is that explanation. But the possibilities are almost endless!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things use radio waves to communicate. AM and FM (obviously!), Wi-fi, bluetooth, remote controls of drones and RC's (&lt;strong&gt;Radio controlled&lt;/strong&gt;... duh), and even cellphones! More and more things are going to communicate wirelessly in the era of IoT. There are even things that unintentionally emit rf signals and these have been used in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tempest_(codename)"&gt;interesting ways&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much interesting very wow. SDR captured me just like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my hands on a Raspberry Pi 2 model B and with Kali linux SDR on it. Just waiting for some hardware to arrive... then research time!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 15:53:28 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2015-06-21:software-defined-radio.html</guid><category>hardware</category><category>sdr</category><category>hacking</category></item><item><title>Twitter and Texting Bots</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/twitter-and-texting-bots.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Her (2013)" class="pure-img" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/josefmonje/josefmonje.github.io/master/images/OR_Her_2013_movie_Wallpaper_52397369.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I joined a hackathon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last January 24-25 I joined my first ever hackathon. I built a Twitter bot and suddenly bots, AI and NLP were so interesting. The Twitter bot I built was simple, it replies to mentions and the reply contained links to what it thinks is relevant based on the wiki back end. Think of it as a proactive google if people used Twitter like google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://Twitter.com/MikeIsaac/status/563729030445539328"&gt;"can someone call my phone -- i cant find it"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;People like talking to other people - but they're not as good as machines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People sometimes use their social networks like search engines. It's now normal to just ask something on Facebook or Twitter and answers come to you. Crowdsource your social graph, it's the easier than sifting through search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies on the otherhand have used Twitter for customer service. Instead of searching for the right forums or contact form online or the e-mail address of customer service, people just say it out loud on Twitter. Instead of hiring more people to answer queries as some companies do, Twitter bots can handle the job better and answer faster automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our gadgets want to understand us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search box is basically a command-line interface for the internet. Beefed up with algorithms, it tries to reduce friction by making it less boolean-y or cli-ish, and prone to typos to get that piece of information faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have Apple's Siri, Google Now, Microsoft's Cortana and the Amazon Echo. We use speech to talk to our gadgets and make it do something. Speech is probably transcribed to text and machines react. Big tech companies have been working on speech to text for some time, it's a difficult problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We will socialize with AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we work in today's Internet of Humans will be different from how we work in tomorrow's Internet of Things. Chat and messaging are back. Yesterday's IRC is now Twitter or Slack. We will have better versions of X, @DearAssistant, and Slackbot. We will expect more from online services in many ways. I can't specify what "more" means but it's within the range of "relating to our humanity". The internet will continue to be "social" but the meaning of social could expand to accommodate human-like interaction with online services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://sites.oreilly.com/odewahn/dds-field-guide/ch10.html"&gt;A Field Guide to the Distributed Development Stack - Real-time Chat and Chatbots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Reilly explores the idea that realtime chat and chatbots will be part of how developers work in their Distributed Development Stack Field Guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As gadgets become smaller, the keyboard will have a difficult time squeezing into the interface of a device. What if the device isn't visual or come to a point where you can't have you hands interact with so easily (iWatches, Google Glasses)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The future will be filled with bots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://continuations.com/post/108271329110/tedxnewyork-big-and-bot-policy-proposals"&gt;Albert Wenger&lt;/a&gt; of USV proposes the idea of being able to be represented by a bot. Think of it like your personal or your person's proxy to the digital world. It's a profound idea and his video explains it well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a time when we'll be talking to our gadgets. We will chat or type commands to our bot underlings. It may or may not include voice. Bots will live in our gadgets or in online servers to do our bidding. We may also have personal bots to talk to other bots or online services. Somehow I feel &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; has that potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm now studying Natural Language Processing concepts based python modules like nltk. There's so much out there I don't know and the net is much more than just for creating web apps. It's so exciting! :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image is from the movie "Her" (2013), a movie I'll soon watch. I don't really watch a lot of movies. But I'll watch this one because it I imagine we will have more of "Her" in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 11:11:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2015-01-30:twitter-and-texting-bots.html</guid><category>python</category><category>tornado</category><category>bots</category><category>AI</category><category>NLP</category><category>Twitter</category><category>SMS</category></item><item><title>Web Development in Python</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/web-development-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last post was about a JavaScript framework. This month it's about Python and the various frameworks I've used. It'll be nice to reflect on these posts next year to benchmark my skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use python when working on server-side code and I've tried several python web development frameworks. As an aside, for me the beauty of python is its readability. Python has powerful features and all, but one of the things I consider important when coding is that I am coding for others. It may be literally so when working on open source projects but it's also benificial for yourself. Imagine when reading old code, debugging and understanding how the code works! Comments would be minimal and less people asking when looking at your code ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first framework I learned was &lt;a href="http://flask.pocoo.org/"&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;. It's a joy to work with on small projects and you can just integrate what's out there when you need it. If you're building something really small or need something really quick, I'd recommend Flask. Learning Flask is so easy, I did it in just an afternoon. You can quickly create stuff with it and see the results. I learn faster when the time between acquiring new knowledge and seeing results from building with it is shorter so starting with Flask was good for me. If you're new to python but not to web development, I would recommend going straight to studying Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also tried &lt;a href="http://www.tornadoweb.org/en/stable/"&gt;Tornado&lt;/a&gt; for a project just for fun. I learned about it during a meetup so I tried it out and made it work right away. I was able to use it for a small project. It's not very far from Flask but I like Tornado because it's async. I won't get into that but async seems like the way to go for projects intended for large audiences while minimizing required resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not the least is &lt;a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;. Django has quite a steep learning curve but like what they say about it, the framework has "batteries included". There's a tutorial on the Django website and it's a few pages long. You can see there's quite a lot of things to learn to effectively django but among the frameworks I've tried, this is probably the best for medium to large projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django code is organized into app modules and within those, the views (controllers, actually, so don't get confused by the label) are in their own files, models in one, admin in another, etc. You get the idea. This is something enforced in Django so it takes a while to get used to if the idea is new to you. After getting used to it, I find that it's a good idea to take with you when working on other frameworks, like the ones I previously mentioned. It just makes sense to but you don't have to take it to the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django comes with a 'free' admin module for looking at your models and doing some basic CRUD. This saves a lot of development time if you have to do it yourself. It tightly integrates with the also built-in authentication module and ORM. This has a lot of advantages to it and some downsides. It you plan on using a database that's not supported by the ORM, you won't be taking advantage of the provided authentication and admin modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I consider when selecting a framework is the size of the project. If it's a small project or a prototype, Flask would do and I'm probably going to use Angular with it as well as a NoSQL database. Otherwise it's almost always Django.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 11:11:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2014-12-31:web-development-in-python.html</guid><category>python</category><category>flask</category><category>tornado</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Famo.us</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/famous.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This month's post is about the &lt;a href="https://famo.us/"&gt;Famo.us&lt;/a&gt; framework. I'm going to dedicate a lot of time to &lt;a href="http://famo.us/university/home/#/"&gt;learn&lt;/a&gt; this javascript framework because I think it's cool in a few ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Famo.us lets developers create smooth complex animations in the browser using its rendering and physics engine. Animations flow as if they were native code on mobile apps, except they're in the browser. Normally, browsers would have a hard time doing this because of the DOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing I really like about it is the integration with &lt;a href="http://angularjs.org"&gt;Angular.js&lt;/a&gt;. I really like Angular because of how you can make some complex things really easily, with minimal code. The learning curve for both frameworks are steep but I'm quite comfortable with Angular now so it's just a matter of time before I can be as confident with Famo.us (I hope!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, I also put up &lt;strong&gt;Famo.us in Manila &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/824687484220358/"&gt;FB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Famo-us-in-Manila-Meetup-Group/"&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; groups&lt;/strong&gt; to bring together people who are curious or want to learn more about Famo.us. I don't think this will be a large group so that'll be better for people who want to get more involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, the &lt;a href="https://josefmonje.com"&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; is now on SSL! Yey!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 11:30:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2014-11-24:famous.html</guid><category>famo.us</category><category>josefmonje.com</category></item><item><title>Jaycees</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/jaycees.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I came back from the JCI Philippines National Convention 2014 at Cagayan De Oro. Aside from all the tech related things in my life, this is one other thing that I spend my time on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was inducted to JCI San Juan Pinaglabanan in 2006/7, couldn't remember, (but it's on my plaque upstairs) and was only partially active/completely inactive for a long time. When I had the chance to connect with the Jaycees from my province I decided to be active again, just as a participant. I was reluctant at first but I was appointed as an officer. This year I'm the Executive Vice President for JCI Cabanatuan Golden Grain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JCI Cabanatuan, as a chapter, is experiencing a revival. These past few months, many are becoming part of the active core group. This is partly because of our experience in hosting the Area Conference for Area One this year. I'm hopeful 2015 will be a good year for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have quite a few friends from my various networks who are also Jaycees from other chapters. It feels good to reconnect with some of them. I look forward to meeting old and new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that this is already too long for a post. I'm not into talking about myself nor reading long posts so I won't put much of that in my blog. I'll leave you with the JCI Creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We believe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That faith in god gives meaning and purpose to human life,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That the brotherhood of man transcends the sovereignty of nations,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That economic justice can best be won by free men through free enterprise,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That government should be of laws rather than of men,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That earth's great treasure lies in human personality,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And that service to humanity is the best work of life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-thumbs-o-up"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 14:00:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2014-10-19:jaycees.html</guid><category>JCI</category><category>jaycees</category></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/hello-world.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my redesigned blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; as my CMS/static site generator, &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; for hosting (yes, you could do that!) and a little &lt;a href="http://angularjs.org/"&gt;Angular.js&lt;/a&gt; to make it look somewhat dynamic. Maybe I'll add some more animations too. For the styling, I used &lt;a href="http://purecss.io/"&gt;Pure.css&lt;/a&gt; as base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to spend more time blogging to help me reflect on my code and show off some practice projects. I'll also blog about some of my other activities and the things I buy online. Hopefully I'll be blogging more about productive stuff rather than personal stuff. Let's see how it goes this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who recognize it, the inspiration for this blog's design is the NES console. &lt;i class="fa fa-heart"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; that machine! Lots of childhood hours well spent in front of the TV. &lt;i class="fa fa-thumbs-o-up"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 15:52:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2014-09-17:hello-world.html</guid><category>josefmonje.com</category><category>blog</category></item></channel></rss>