<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Josef Monje</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://josefmonje.com/feeds%5Cjosef-monje.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 11:30:53 +0800</lastBuildDate><item><title>Famo.us</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/famous.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This month's post is about the &lt;a href="https://famo.us/"&gt;Famo.us&lt;/a&gt; framework. I'm going to dedicate a lot of time to &lt;a href="http://famo.us/university/home/#/"&gt;learn&lt;/a&gt; this javascript framework because I think it's cool in a few ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Famo.us lets developers create smooth complex animations in the browser using its rendering and physics engine. Animations flow as if they were native code on mobile apps, except they're in the browser. Normally, browsers would have a hard time doing this because of the DOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing I really like about it is the integration with &lt;a href="http://angularjs.org"&gt;Angular.js&lt;/a&gt;. I really like Angular because of how you can make some complex things really easily, with minimal code. The learning curve for both frameworks are steep but I'm quite comfortable with Angular now so it's just a matter of time before I can be as confident with Famo.us (I hope!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, the &lt;a href="https://josefmonje.com"&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; is now on SSL! Yey!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 11:30:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2014-11-24:famous.html</guid><category>famo.us</category><category>josefmonje.com</category></item><item><title>Jaycees</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/jaycees.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I came back from the JCI Philippines National Convention 2014 at Cagayan De Oro. Aside from all the tech related things in my life, this is one other thing that I spend my time on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was inducted to JCI San Juan Pinaglabanan in 2006/7, couldn't remember, (but it's on my plaque upstairs) and was only partially active/completely inactive for a long time. When I had the chance to connect with the Jaycees from my province I decided to be active again, just as a participant. I was reluctant at first but I was appointed as an officer. This year I'm the Executive Vice President for JCI Cabanatuan Golden Grain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JCI Cabanatuan, as a chapter, is experiencing a revival. These past few months, many are becoming part of the active core group. This is partly because of our experience in hosting the Area Conference for Area One this year. I'm hopeful 2015 will be a good year for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have quite a few friends from my various networks who are also Jaycees from other chapters. It feels good to reconnect with some of them. I look forward to meeting old and new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that this is already too long for a post. I'm not into talking about myself nor reading long posts so I won't put much of that in my blog. I'll leave you with the JCI Creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We believe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That faith in god gives meaning and purpose to human life,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That the brotherhood of man transcends the sovereignty of nations,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That economic justice can best be won by free men through free enterprise,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That government should be of laws rather than of men,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That earth's great treasure lies in human personality,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And that service to humanity is the best work of life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-thumbs-o-up"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 14:00:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2014-10-19:jaycees.html</guid><category>JCI</category><category>jaycees</category></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://josefmonje.com/hello-world.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my redesigned blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; as my CMS/static site generator, &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; for hosting (yes, you could do that!) and a little &lt;a href="http://angularjs.org/"&gt;Angular.js&lt;/a&gt; to make it look somewhat dynamic. Maybe I'll add some more animations too. For the styling, I used &lt;a href="http://purecss.io/"&gt;Pure.css&lt;/a&gt; as base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to spend more time blogging to help me reflect on my code and show off some practice projects. I'll also blog about some of my other activities and the things I buy online. Hopefully I'll be blogging more about productive stuff rather than personal stuff. Let's see how it goes this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who recognize it, the inspiration for this blog's design is the NES console. &lt;i class="fa fa-heart"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; that machine! Lots of childhood hours well spent in front of the TV. &lt;i class="fa fa-thumbs-o-up"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josef Monje</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 15:52:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:josefmonje.com,2014-09-17:hello-world.html</guid><category>josefmonje.com</category><category>blog</category></item></channel></rss>